In our previous lecture on loops, we briefly introduced you to Python graphics, which is known as
Turtle graphics.
So now our game we are going to be making is using turtle graphics.
So let's get into this and see how we create this game before.
I've already told you that we have modules and if we need a user module we have to import it.
You can see this first statement over here on line one.
I'm importing turtle.
So in order to use turtle graphics your first line has to be import turtle.
If we don't do that then we cannot use any of the methods you can see below.
Okay then these lines here are basically just setting up our screen when we run the program.
Let me just run it quickly.
You can see the screen is created and this screen is of size 1000 pixels by 600.
And this next variable here is just a screen variable.
It's just the variable that you use whenever you want to do anything to do with the screen.
But you need to have this.
Yeah.
So as soon as you start you out.
So as soon as you start your coding, tap in these two lines.
And without this line nothing is going to work.
Okay.
Now let's get into creating our turtles.
For this game to work, we need two turtles.
We need the goalie and we need the ball.
This line over here, line number six creates our goalie.
So what we're doing here is we've created a variable called goalie.
And we have assigned it to this function over here, which is basically like what you've seen before.
It's the turtle class.
So we have to say turtle and then dot turtle, which is actually a method in the turtle class called
turtle.
And this method over here creates a new turtle object.
So we've created this object here for the goalie one turtle for the goalie.
And then below it we have created another turtle object for the ball using this turtle function found
in the turtle class.
Okay.
So that would create our two different turtle objects.
Now for this game to work, we need these objects to be in a specific position, and we also want to
make them a bit more interesting and maybe make them look a certain way.
And yeah, just to make them a little bit more exciting.
So let's start off with the ball.
This first line here is basically just lifting the turtle pan.
So if you remember in our example we showed you in the loop, it was almost like a drawing that we were
doing.
And there was this pan that was drawing around and around the screen.
But we don't want that line when the turtle moves around.
So we want to lift the pen up so you can actually try in your own code.
This code has been posted below.
So tap out the code or copy and paste it, but rather try tapping it and comment this out and see what
happens if it has been commented out.
Okay, so we've lifted up the pan.
Then we want our ball to be in the shape of a circle.
We want the size to be two.
I mean, you can change this to whatever you want.
Maybe you want a giant ball or tiny ball.
Play around with it.
We've made the color white and we've made the ball speed of one.
Now, one is actually the slowest speed a turtle can move up.
Um, if you go high up all the way up to ten, ten becomes the fastest.
Then this function here called ball dot set heading.
This is setting the ball to face West.
And that's because our ball is going west towards the goalie.
Okay.
So that is just some of the things that we want our ball to do and what we want our ball to look like.
And basically the same down here for the goalie, it is the exact same thing that's happening up here,
except we have made the shape a turtle, changed the speed, we've made the goalie face upwards, and
we have told the goalie to go to position -300 as the x axis and zero as the y axis on the screen.
So think about the screen as a x y plane.
And basically you will have to play around with these numbers to get the perfect position.
But you can see here this is -300 and it is on zero for the y.
So basically these are our little turtles we've made.
There is our ball.
There is our goalie.
And yeah after this you've made your first two turtles and play around a bit and see what happens if
you change some code around.